<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aviation on So much to learn, so much to do...</title>
    <link>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aviation on So much to learn, so much to do...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2023 Pierre Cauchois</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//pierreca.github.io/aviation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying around Maui</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/maui_county/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/maui_county/</guid>
      <description>Flying around Maui, Molokai and Lanai If like me you would like to fly yourself around Maui, I highly recommend Maui Aviators at Kahului. The following is pretty much my recollection of the flight I did with them that includes a checkout and a slightly customized version of their Circle Maui County flight with instruction tidbits I got from the CFI I flew with, Steve Ludlow.
Mandatory boring disclaimer: There is obviously a lot more to flying the Hawaiian islands than what is described below - this isn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be instruction, official source of information such as charts and chart supplements, or a substitute for good ADM or risk management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Pictures from Aircrafts</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/airplane_photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/airplane_photography/</guid>
      <description>Tips for taking pictures from airplanes and helicopters Wear dark clothes: bright/light-colored clothes will create reflections on the windows Consider using a polarizing filter to get rid of glare (but know how to use it - and understand the consequences of it too&amp;hellip;) Go manual or go home: autofocus will be tripped by reflections and the speed at which things are moving Bracketing is of no use if you&amp;rsquo;re taking pictures of what is outside the airplane: you&amp;rsquo;re moving too fast Bracketing is great if you&amp;rsquo;re taking pictures inside the plane and still want to see what&amp;rsquo;s outside the window Bring limited gear: changing lenses and fiddling with equipment in a small cockpit is difficult Try to plan the flight and what you want to take pictures off (ask the pilot for the flight route!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
