<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pierre on Making, Flying and Diving</title>
    <link>//pierreca.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I&#39;m Pierre on Making, Flying and Diving</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Pierre Cauchois</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//pierreca.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying around Maui</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/maui_county/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/maui_county/</guid>
      <description>Flying around Maui, Molokai and Lanai If like me you would like to fly yourself around Maui, I highly recommend Maui Aviators at Kahului. The following is pretty much my recollection of the flight I did with them that includes a checkout and a slightly customized version of their Circle Maui County flight with instruction tidbits I got from the CFI I flew with, Steve Ludlow.
Mandatory boring disclaimer: There is obviously a lot more to flying the Hawaiian islands than what is described below - this isn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be instruction, official source of information such as charts and chart supplements, or a substitute for good ADM or risk management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Pictures from Aircrafts</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/airplane_photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/airplane_photography/</guid>
      <description>Tips for taking pictures from airplanes and helicopters  Wear dark clothes: bright/light-colored clothes will create reflections on the windows Consider using a polarizing filter to get rid of glare (but know how to use it - and understand the consequences of it too&amp;hellip;) Go manual or go home: autofocus will be tripped by reflections and the speed at which things are moving Bracketing is of no use if you&amp;rsquo;re taking pictures of what is outside the airplane: you&amp;rsquo;re moving too fast Bracketing is great if you&amp;rsquo;re taking pictures inside the plane and still want to see what&amp;rsquo;s outside the window Bring limited gear: changing lenses and fiddling with equipment in a small cockpit is difficult Try to plan the flight and what you want to take pictures off (ask the pilot for the flight route!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple 3D Model of the Intel Galileo Board</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</guid>
      <description>I published a very simplistic 3d model of Intels Galileo (v1) board on Github years ago. It was built using OpenScad and the code is available as well as the exported STL file.
![Galileo 3D model image](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pierreca/Galileo/master/Images/galileo_v1_3d.PNG Galileo 3D model image)
I rely on 3D models a lot during the design of any project because its a way for me to cut on prototyping costs and times. One thing that often leaves me wanting more with a lot of projects I see from makers is the fact that it stays on a breadboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Bad Reasons Not To Finish Projects And How To Finish Anyway</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/bad_reasons_finish_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/bad_reasons_finish_projects/</guid>
      <description>Years of tinkering with electronics and building apps on week-ends and evenings, and recently I have found myself thinking that I never really finish anything. It has been bugging me to a point where I felt really bad about it The weird thing is, its not at all the same at work. Im focused and I always have a clear idea of whats done, whats expected and I know when and how to deliver things on time and meeting my team QA standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Coffee Table With Engine Blocks</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I had seen coffee table on the british TV show called Top Gear (made from a Jaguar V12 engine) I wanted to have an engine-based coffee table. A quick search on the Web showed that anyone can buy that for just over a thousand bucks but I also found a handful of results from people who had done that before and were showing it on some forums: so I set out to build my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/diving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/diving/</guid>
      <description>Where I dive, who I dive with, what I&amp;rsquo;m certified for and what I use as part of my diving experiences
Dive Trips  Maui (w/ Lahaina Divers &amp;amp; Maui Dreams) Big Island (w/ Kona Honu Divers) Cozumel (w/ Dive Paradise)  PNW Dive Shops  Underwater Sports 8 Diving Systems Silent World Diving Systems Tacoma Scuba  PNW Dive Sites  Redondo Beach Les Davis Dickman Mills Three-tree Alki Cove 2 Point Defiance North Wall (w/ Bandito Charters) Zee&amp;rsquo;s Reef (w/ Bandito Charters) Sund Rock Lobster Shop Wall  Certifications  Open Water Diver (SSI) Advanced Open Water Diver (PADI) Rescue Diver (PADI) Advanced Nitrox and Intro to Deco Procedures (TDI)  Software  Multideco Subsurface  PNW Gear  Hollis backplate Mares single &amp;amp; double donut wings Santi e-Motion+ Dry suit 100HP single and double cylinders with Apeks XTX50 Regs AL80 and AL40 Deco cylinders with Hollis Deco Regs Hollis F1 fins  Travel Gear  Backplate or Scubapro Hydros Pro Atomics B2 Reg Scubapro Nova fins Subapro Everflex 3mm wetsuit Sharkskin  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Places for Makers in Seattle</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</guid>
      <description>18 months ago, I moved from Paris, France to Seattle, WA. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few personal projects that have taken me around the Seattle area in search for maker resources and shops Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found so far!
Meetups Hardware Happy Hour HHH Meetup
Friendly bunch of folks mostly talking about electronics and 3d printing. Meet every month either in Seattle (Optimism Brewing) or in Redmond (Postdoc brewery).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of podcasts I listen to&amp;hellip;
Software  Go Time JS Party  Hardware  The Amp Hour The Macrofab Engineering Podcast Embedded.fm  Infosec  Darknet Diaries Malicious Life Unnamed Reverse Engineering Podcast Hackable  Dropped Off&amp;hellip; Loved these but there are only so many hours in the week and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily relate to my interests (as much) anymore.
 Test &amp;amp; Code Coding Blocks Talk Python to Me Python Bytes HBR Ideacast Dear HBR Developer Tea Hidden Brain (NPR) TED Radio Hour (NPR) Freakonomics Radio Making it with Jimmy Di Resta, Bob Clagett and David Picciuto  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reads</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/reads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/reads/</guid>
      <description>Finished Management &amp;amp; Tech  Hooked: How to Build Habit-Forming Products (Nir Eyal) Stop the BS (Shane Mac) The Burning Entrepreneur (Brad Feld) Hit Refresh (Satya Nadella) Mindset: The New Psychology of Success (Carol S. Dweck) Non-Violent Communication (Marshall B. Rosenberg) Tribal Leadership (Dave Logan, John King, Halee Fischer-Wright) Never Split the Difference: Negotiating As If Your Life Depended On It (Chris Voss) The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path (Camille Fournier) Talking with Tech Leads: From Novices to Practitioners (Patrick Kua) First, Break All the Rules (Gallup Press) Leaders Eat Last (Simon Sinek) Rework (Jason Fried) Switch: How to Change Things When Change Is Hard (Chip &amp;amp; Dan Heath) The Power of When (Michael Breus) The Mythical Man-Month (Fred Brooks) The Effective Executive (Peter Drucker) Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and Devops (Nicole Forsgren, PhD with Jez Humble and Gene Kim) Designing Distributed Systems (Brendan Burns) Zero Trust Networks: Building Secure Systems in Untrusted Networks (Evan Gilman, Doug Barth)  Making  The Hardware Hacker (Andrew &amp;ldquo;bunnie&amp;rdquo; Huang) Maker Pro: Essays on Making a Living as a Maker (John Baichtal &amp;amp; others) Every Tool&amp;rsquo;s a Hammer: Life is What You Make It (Adam Savage) Good Clean Fun: Misadventures in Sawdust At Offerman Woodshop (Nick Offerman)  Fiction  Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance (Robert M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>