<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pierre on So much to learn, so much to do...</title>
    <link>//pierreca.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I&#39;m Pierre on So much to learn, so much to do...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2023 Pierre Cauchois</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//pierreca.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying around Maui</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/maui_county/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/maui_county/</guid>
      <description>Flying around Maui, Molokai and Lanai If like me you would like to fly yourself around Maui, I highly recommend Maui Aviators at Kahului. The following is pretty much my recollection of the flight I did with them that includes a checkout and a slightly customized version of their Circle Maui County flight with instruction tidbits I got from the CFI I flew with, Steve Ludlow.
Mandatory boring disclaimer: There is obviously a lot more to flying the Hawaiian islands than what is described below - this isn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be instruction, official source of information such as charts and chart supplements, or a substitute for good ADM or risk management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Pictures from Aircrafts</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/airplane_photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/aviation/airplane_photography/</guid>
      <description>Tips for taking pictures from airplanes and helicopters Wear dark clothes: bright/light-colored clothes will create reflections on the windows Consider using a polarizing filter to get rid of glare (but know how to use it - and understand the consequences of it too&amp;hellip;) Go manual or go home: autofocus will be tripped by reflections and the speed at which things are moving Bracketing is of no use if you&amp;rsquo;re taking pictures of what is outside the airplane: you&amp;rsquo;re moving too fast Bracketing is great if you&amp;rsquo;re taking pictures inside the plane and still want to see what&amp;rsquo;s outside the window Bring limited gear: changing lenses and fiddling with equipment in a small cockpit is difficult Try to plan the flight and what you want to take pictures off (ask the pilot for the flight route!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple 3D Model of the Intel Galileo Board</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</guid>
      <description>I published a very simplistic 3d model of Intels Galileo (v1) board on Github years ago. It was built using OpenScad and the code is available as well as the exported STL file.
![Galileo 3D model image](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pierreca/Galileo/master/Images/galileo_v1_3d.PNG Galileo 3D model image)
I rely on 3D models a lot during the design of any project because its a way for me to cut on prototyping costs and times. One thing that often leaves me wanting more with a lot of projects I see from makers is the fact that it stays on a breadboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>In no particular order, what&amp;rsquo;s on my bookshelves. Generally speaking, those I like more will find their way to the top of each list.
Rating system:
All time favorite. Dare I say, lifechanging: ❤ Insightful: 🤯 Practical: 🛠 Management When I became the manager of a team back during my time at Microsoft, I had confidence in my technical abilities, but not really in my ability to be of service for the people who now reported to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Coffee Table With Engine Blocks</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I had seen coffee table on the british TV show called Top Gear (made from a Jaguar V12 engine) I wanted to have an engine-based coffee table. A quick search on the Web showed that anyone can buy that for just over a thousand bucks but I also found a handful of results from people who had done that before and were showing it on some forums: so I set out to build my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an S.A.O. for the Defcon 31 Badge</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/defcon_31_sao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/defcon_31_sao/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of my career I have been to a number of conferences, as an attendee, a vendor, and a speaker. I love conferences. In recent years though, my job hasn&amp;rsquo;t encouraged participating, so I found myself curating conferences I would want to go to for personal reasons rather than professional ones. The Hackaday Supercon, Crowdsupply Teardown, and Defcon, always make the list. There are &amp;ldquo;grown up&amp;rdquo; conferences for makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Iconic Casio Watches</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/casios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/casios/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if there are more popular, more pervasive watches than the Casio F91-W and A178-W models. I had one as a kid, like millions of other people, and loved it, but didn&amp;rsquo;t think much about it when I grew up. Until I met Joey Castillo and his project, Sensor Watch at the Hackaday Supercon 2022. Joey and the sensor-watch contributors designed a replacement PCB for those Casio models, with a programmable MCU and an extension port that could be used for example for a temperature sensor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/diving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/diving/</guid>
      <description>Where I dive, who I dive with, what I&amp;rsquo;m certified for and what I use as part of my diving experiences
Dive Trips Maui (w/ Lahaina Divers &amp;amp; Maui Dreams) Big Island (w/ Kona Honu Divers) Cozumel (w/ Dive Paradise) PNW Dive Shops Underwater Sports 8 Diving Systems Silent World Diving Systems Tacoma Scuba PNW Dive Sites Redondo Beach Les Davis Dickman Mills Three-tree Alki Cove 2 Point Defiance North Wall (w/ Bandito Charters) Zee&amp;rsquo;s Reef (w/ Bandito Charters) Sund Rock Lobster Shop Wall Certifications Open Water Diver (SSI) Advanced Open Water Diver (PADI) Rescue Diver (PADI) Advanced Nitrox and Intro to Deco Procedures (TDI) Software Multideco Subsurface PNW Gear Hollis backplate Mares single &amp;amp; double donut wings Santi e-Motion+ Dry suit 100HP single and double cylinders with Apeks XTX50 Regs AL80 and AL40 Deco cylinders with Hollis Deco Regs Hollis F1 fins Travel Gear Backplate or Scubapro Hydros Pro Atomics B2 Reg Scubapro Nova fins Subapro Everflex 3mm wetsuit Sharkskin </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Places for Makers in Seattle</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</guid>
      <description>18 months ago, I moved from Paris, France to Seattle, WA. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few personal projects that have taken me around the Seattle area in search for maker resources and shops Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found so far!
Meetups Hardware Happy Hour HHH Meetup
Friendly bunch of folks mostly talking about electronics and 3d printing. Meet every month either in Seattle (Optimism Brewing) or in Redmond (Postdoc brewery).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain-Biking</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/mtb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/mtb/</guid>
      <description>Getting back into mountain-biking in my late 30&amp;rsquo;s after a nearly 15 year hiatus was the best thing I did for my mental health. For many reasons I&amp;rsquo;m a happier person when I can ride a bike. There&amp;rsquo;s even decent science to explain why. It&amp;rsquo;s not just the fitness aspect, but also the chemical cocktail generated by &amp;ldquo;flow sports&amp;rdquo; that is guaranteed to have a positive impact on mood as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of podcasts I listen to&amp;hellip;
Software Go Time JS Party Hardware The Amp Hour The Macrofab Engineering Podcast Embedded.fm Infosec Darknet Diaries Malicious Life Unnamed Reverse Engineering Podcast Hackable Dropped Off&amp;hellip; Loved these but there are only so many hours in the week and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily relate to my interests (as much) anymore.
Test &amp;amp; Code Coding Blocks Talk Python to Me Python Bytes HBR Ideacast Dear HBR Developer Tea Hidden Brain (NPR) TED Radio Hour (NPR) Freakonomics Radio Making it with Jimmy Di Resta, Bob Clagett and David Picciuto </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woodworking</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/woodworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/woodworking/</guid>
      <description>My foray into woodworking started with the need to create a nicer box for the nixie clock I had built. it was also a good excuse to learn how to use a laser cutter for thin wood stock. Learning about various wood species and finishing techniques got me more interested in the medium and I found myself wanting to build more things out of wood. This led me to take a few classes, and I started thinking of small things I could make in the space I had at the time, that could become gifts for friends and family.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
