<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Making, Flying and Diving</title>
    <link>//pierreca.github.io/categories/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Making, Flying and Diving</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Pierre Cauchois</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="//pierreca.github.io/categories/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reads</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/reads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/reads/</guid>
      <description>Finished Management &amp;amp; Tech  Hooked: How to Build Habit-Forming Products (Nir Eyal) Stop the BS (Shane Mac) The Burning Entrepreneur (Brad Feld) Hit Refresh (Satya Nadella) Mindset: The New Psychology of Success (Carol S. Dweck) Non-Violent Communication (Marshall B. Rosenberg) Tribal Leadership (Dave Logan, John King, Halee Fischer-Wright) Never Split the Difference: Negotiating As If Your Life Depended On It (Chris Voss) The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path (Camille Fournier) Talking with Tech Leads: From Novices to Practitioners (Patrick Kua) First, Break All the Rules (Gallup Press) Leaders Eat Last (Simon Sinek) Rework (Jason Fried) Switch: How to Change Things When Change Is Hard (Chip &amp;amp; Dan Heath) The Power of When (Michael Breus) The Mythical Man-Month (Fred Brooks) The Effective Executive (Peter Drucker) Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and Devops (Nicole Forsgren, PhD with Jez Humble and Gene Kim) Designing Distributed Systems (Brendan Burns) Zero Trust Networks: Building Secure Systems in Untrusted Networks (Evan Gilman, Doug Barth)  Making  The Hardware Hacker (Andrew &amp;ldquo;bunnie&amp;rdquo; Huang) Maker Pro: Essays on Making a Living as a Maker (John Baichtal &amp;amp; others) Every Tool&amp;rsquo;s a Hammer: Life is What You Make It (Adam Savage) Good Clean Fun: Misadventures in Sawdust At Offerman Woodshop (Nick Offerman)  Fiction  Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance (Robert M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>