<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on So much to learn, so much to do...</title>
    <link>//pierreca.github.io/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on So much to learn, so much to do...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2023 Pierre Cauchois</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//pierreca.github.io/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Simple 3D Model of the Intel Galileo Board</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</guid>
      <description>I published a very simplistic 3d model of Intels Galileo (v1) board on Github years ago. It was built using OpenScad and the code is available as well as the exported STL file.
![Galileo 3D model image](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pierreca/Galileo/master/Images/galileo_v1_3d.PNG Galileo 3D model image)
I rely on 3D models a lot during the design of any project because its a way for me to cut on prototyping costs and times. One thing that often leaves me wanting more with a lot of projects I see from makers is the fact that it stays on a breadboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Coffee Table With Engine Blocks</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I had seen coffee table on the british TV show called Top Gear (made from a Jaguar V12 engine) I wanted to have an engine-based coffee table. A quick search on the Web showed that anyone can buy that for just over a thousand bucks but I also found a handful of results from people who had done that before and were showing it on some forums: so I set out to build my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an S.A.O. for the Defcon 31 Badge</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/defcon_31_sao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/defcon_31_sao/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of my career I have been to a number of conferences, as an attendee, a vendor, and a speaker. I love conferences. In recent years though, my job hasn&amp;rsquo;t encouraged participating, so I found myself curating conferences I would want to go to for personal reasons rather than professional ones. The Hackaday Supercon, Crowdsupply Teardown, and Defcon, always make the list. There are &amp;ldquo;grown up&amp;rdquo; conferences for makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Iconic Casio Watches</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/casios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/casios/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if there are more popular, more pervasive watches than the Casio F91-W and A178-W models. I had one as a kid, like millions of other people, and loved it, but didn&amp;rsquo;t think much about it when I grew up. Until I met Joey Castillo and his project, Sensor Watch at the Hackaday Supercon 2022. Joey and the sensor-watch contributors designed a replacement PCB for those Casio models, with a programmable MCU and an extension port that could be used for example for a temperature sensor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Places for Makers in Seattle</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</guid>
      <description>18 months ago, I moved from Paris, France to Seattle, WA. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few personal projects that have taken me around the Seattle area in search for maker resources and shops Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found so far!
Meetups Hardware Happy Hour HHH Meetup
Friendly bunch of folks mostly talking about electronics and 3d printing. Meet every month either in Seattle (Optimism Brewing) or in Redmond (Postdoc brewery).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects with writeups Making an SAO for the Defcon 31 Badge Customizing iconic casio watches A list of interesting places for makers around Seattle Engine Coffee Table Projects without writeups Maple+Neopixel Clock LED-lighted TAC chart for real-time weather display Hackaday.io Dashboards and utilities for jenkins and github LED Matrix board driven by a Spark Core Hackaday.io Simple 3D model of the Intel Galileo Github LightClock v2 Hackaday.io Naive implementation of Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game Of Life on a Peggy 2 LED Matrix .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woodworking</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/woodworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/woodworking/</guid>
      <description>My foray into woodworking started with the need to create a nicer box for the nixie clock I had built. it was also a good excuse to learn how to use a laser cutter for thin wood stock. Learning about various wood species and finishing techniques got me more interested in the medium and I found myself wanting to build more things out of wood. This led me to take a few classes, and I started thinking of small things I could make in the space I had at the time, that could become gifts for friends and family.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
