<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on Making, Flying and Diving</title>
    <link>//pierreca.github.io/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on Making, Flying and Diving</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Pierre Cauchois</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//pierreca.github.io/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple 3D Model of the Intel Galileo Board</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/galileo_3d_model/</guid>
      <description>I published a very simplistic 3d model of Intels Galileo (v1) board on Github years ago. It was built using OpenScad and the code is available as well as the exported STL file.
![Galileo 3D model image](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pierreca/Galileo/master/Images/galileo_v1_3d.PNG Galileo 3D model image)
I rely on 3D models a lot during the design of any project because its a way for me to cut on prototyping costs and times. One thing that often leaves me wanting more with a lot of projects I see from makers is the fact that it stays on a breadboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Articles  A list of interesting places for makers around Seattle 7 Bad Reasons Not To Finish Projects And How To Finish Anyway  Hardware (or Hardware-related)  Maple+Neopixel Clock LED-lighted TAC chart for real-time weather display Hackaday.io Dashboards and utilities for jenkins and github LED Matrix board driven by a Spark Core Hackaday.io Simple 3D model of the Intel Galileo Github LightClock v2 Hackster.io| Hackaday.io Raspberry-Pi Home Gateway (codename Tyler) Naive implementation of Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game Of Life on a Peggy 2 LED Matrix .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Bad Reasons Not To Finish Projects And How To Finish Anyway</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/bad_reasons_finish_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/bad_reasons_finish_projects/</guid>
      <description>Years of tinkering with electronics and building apps on week-ends and evenings, and recently I have found myself thinking that I never really finish anything. It has been bugging me to a point where I felt really bad about it The weird thing is, its not at all the same at work. Im focused and I always have a clear idea of whats done, whats expected and I know when and how to deliver things on time and meeting my team QA standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Coffee Table With Engine Blocks</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/engine_coffee_table/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I had seen coffee table on the british TV show called Top Gear (made from a Jaguar V12 engine) I wanted to have an engine-based coffee table. A quick search on the Web showed that anyone can buy that for just over a thousand bucks but I also found a handful of results from people who had done that before and were showing it on some forums: so I set out to build my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Places for Makers in Seattle</title>
      <link>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//pierreca.github.io/projects/maker_places_seattle/</guid>
      <description>18 months ago, I moved from Paris, France to Seattle, WA. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few personal projects that have taken me around the Seattle area in search for maker resources and shops Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found so far!
Meetups Hardware Happy Hour HHH Meetup
Friendly bunch of folks mostly talking about electronics and 3d printing. Meet every month either in Seattle (Optimism Brewing) or in Redmond (Postdoc brewery).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>